937-238-9762

bradford.loesch@gmail.com

bradfordloesch.com

linkedin.com/in/bradford-loesch

github.com/bradford-loesch

# **Bradford Loesch**

# FRONT END WEB DEVELOPER

Chicago, IL

Former chemist turned coder. Worked in both industry and academia, in research labs and manufacturing. Committed to improving processes and methods. Observed a crucial need for applications that enhance the productivity of analytical scientists. Passionate about bridging the gap between science and development.

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML	Javascript	Rails	Vagrant
CSS	Python	Flask	Virtual Box
jQuery	Ruby	Django	Git/Version Control
Bootstrap	C++	Express	RSpec/Capybara
Materialize	IDL	Node	unittest
Angular	Labview	Gems	SQL/NoSQL

Additional scientific and engineering experience:

Spectroscopy, analytical chemistry, organic synthesis, thermomechanical testing, microscopy, laser maintenance, troubleshooting manufacturing issues, and supplier approvals

### **PROJECTS**

**MY PORTFOLIO PAGE** 

Showcase for myself and my projects

Designed in MEAN, utilizing Materialize as a front end

framework, and a MongoDB database Deployed to Amazon Web Services

**ENGLEWOOD OPTOMETRY** 

Business website for a locally owned and operated

optometry practice

Designed with Ruby on Rails, utilizing Bootstrap as a front

end framework

TRAVEL SCHEDULING APP

Web app for coordinating travel plans, with ability to create

and join trips with data validation

Desgined with Python and Django, utilizing Bootstrap as a front end framework, and a Postgres SQL database

## **EDUCATION**

DEVELOPER IN RESIDENCE

Coding Dojo Chicago, IL (2016) An immersive full stack development program. Graduated with a Black Belt (highest earning of achievement) in Python/Django, Ruby on Rails, and MEAN Stack Over 1000 hours of coding experience, and a working proficiency in JavaScript, AngularJS, SQL and NoSQL databases, as well as a wide range of other frameworks and libraries

#### CHEMISTRY M.S.

University of Rochester Rochester, NY (2003 – 2007)

Studied enriched single chirality, single-walled carbon nanotubes (SWNTs) spectroscopic properties
Maintained and improved ultrafast transient absorption setup and optical table, greatly reducing data collection times
Probed the electronic relaxation rates for single chirality enriched samples of SWNTs

#### CHEMISTRY B.S.

Rochester Institute of Technology
Rochester, NY (2003 – 2007)

Founder of Chem Club, promoting chemistry in the community and providing chemistry tutoring Synthesized novel, transparent, non-linear optical polymers intended for use in optical switching Semester long cultural immersion, study abroad program in Perugia, Italy: ILR level 2 in Italian

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### **CODING DOJO**

Teaching Assistant
Chicago, IL (2017 – present)

Focused on Python, utilizing both Flask and Django Assist with curriculum and lesson planning Facilitate students' understanding of the material

#### **BRIDGESTONE-FIRESTONE**

Reinforcement Engineer Akron, OH (2007 – 2008)

Performed quality assurance for current products
Approved new suppliers for steel cord, reducing production costs and increasing quality
Worked with manufacturing and suppliers to correct quality

Worked with manufacturing and suppliers to correct quality issues and ensure production to reduce downtime

#### AMGEN. INC.

Small Molecule Chemist Thousand Oaks, CA (2006) Synthesized indoles with varying ring sizes and purified products using column chromatography
Characterized products using LC-MS and NMR
Optimized synthetic yields of Fischer indole syntheses

# ROCHESTER INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY

Honors Research Fellow Rochester, NY (2005)

Performed organic synthesis of optically active polymer pendant and polymer components
Characterized synthesis products with FTIR, NMR, and

Mass Spectrometry
Polymerized 2 and 3 component polymer systems

# CORNERSTONE RESEARCH GROUP

Polymer Chemist Beavercreek, OH (2004)

Used DSC, TGA, and mechanical testing to monitor quality of production polymers, and for contracted testing Developed a new polymer activator for current products, decreasing materials costs

# PRESENTATIONS AND PUBLICATIONS

2011 Annual Fall Meeting of the Materials Research Society, Boston, MA: Oral Presentation Title: Multiple Exciton Generation in Single Chirality Single-Walled Carbon Nanotubes

Bright Fluorescence from Individual Single-Walled Carbon Nanotubes Nano Lett., 2011, 11 (4), pp 1636–1640